<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>k3s on Ramblings about all things technical</title><link>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/tags/k3s/</link><description>Recent content in k3s on Ramblings about all things technical</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:55:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jamesclonk.io/tags/k3s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy a K3s cluster with Terraform</title><link>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/kubernetes-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 17:55:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/kubernetes-with-terraform/</guid><description>Since Infrastructure-as-Code is all the rage out there (and for good reason, you&amp;rsquo;re a fool if your entire tech stack is not 100% rebuildable and reproducible in an idempotent way!), I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered if I should write and open-source a project that&amp;rsquo;s written entirely as a Terraform module only and that would spin up a Kubernetes cluster on Swisscom&amp;rsquo;s public Infrastructure-as-a-Service offering, DCS+ (Dynamic Computing Services), which is based on VMware vCloud Director.</description></item><item><title>My own personal Kubernetes</title><link>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/my-own-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 12:49:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/my-own-kubernetes/</guid><description>Managed Kubernetes? On my journey where I was (unfortunately) forced to migrate from Cloud Foundry to Kubernetes, I first went with a &amp;ldquo;Managed Kubernetes-as-a-Service&amp;rdquo; offering. You can read about that here.
But it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long for problems and issues to start emerging. The cluster not being on exactly the version I wanted it to be, pre-installed components that didn&amp;rsquo;t behave they way I wanted (nginx ingress controller for example), price hikes and occasional outages, not really a lot of insight into the behind the scenes of my cluster, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>