<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dns on Ramblings about all things technical</title><link>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/tags/dns/</link><description>Recent content in Dns on Ramblings about all things technical</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 16:06:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jamesclonk.io/tags/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Container Networking with Cloud Foundry</title><link>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/container-networking-with-cloud-foundry/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 16:06:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/container-networking-with-cloud-foundry/</guid><description>Container-to-Container Networking on the Swisscom Application Cloud allows for secure and fast direct TCP and UDP communication between your applications. And thanks to its built in Application Service Discovery your app containers will easily be able to locate each other.
The Swisscom Application Cloud uses the open-source distribution of Cloud Foundry to provide you with a managed platform-as-a-service. Ever since the platforms official release we&amp;rsquo;ve continually been adding and implementing new features, and one of these is the Container-to-Container Networking.</description></item><item><title>Service Discovery with Consul</title><link>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/service-discovery-with-consul/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 14:40:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/service-discovery-with-consul/</guid><description>What is Service Discovery? In a cloud environment applications can change often, containers can move around, and VMs can be shutdown and recreated at any time. How do you keep track of where your databases or other services or applications are located and what their IP addresses are? Modern microservices architecture requires the introduction of &amp;ldquo;Service Discovery&amp;rdquo;.
Service discovery is the means to provide a way for automatic detection of applications and services in the cloud, to keep track of the location of service instances with dynamically assigned IP address.</description></item></channel></rss>