<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud foundry on Ramblings about all things technical</title><link>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/tags/cloud-foundry/</link><description>Recent content in cloud foundry on Ramblings about all things technical</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 11:23:54 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jamesclonk.io/tags/cloud-foundry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using a Service Broker in Cloud Foundry</title><link>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/using-a-service-broker-in-cloud-foundry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 11:23:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/using-a-service-broker-in-cloud-foundry/</guid><description>OSBAPI? The Open Service Broker API (OSBAPI) is a specification that defines a common language for service providers that your cloud native applications can use to manage cloud services without lockin.
OSBAPI allows independent software vendors, service providers and developers to easily integrate and consume services for workloads running on cloud native platforms such as the Swisscom Application Cloud, which is based on Cloud Foundry and Kubernetes. The specification describes a simple set of API endpoints which can be used to provision, access and manage various service offerings, and has been adopted by many different platforms and thousands of service providers by now.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Foundry and Prometheus</title><link>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/cloud-foundry-and-prometheus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 11:40:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/cloud-foundry-and-prometheus/</guid><description>Where are my metrics? A Cloud Foundry story Loggregator The Loggregator in Cloud Foundry is the system behind the scenes that&amp;rsquo;s responsible for gathering and streaming logs and metrics about user apps. It also gathers and streams metrics from Cloud Foundry components itself and health metrics from other platform VMs. Loggregator allows you to view these logs and metrics either through the Loggregator CF-CLI plugins or through various third-party services and consumers, like for example the Cloud-Controller (API), a Firehose Nozzle or a Log-Cache endpoint.</description></item><item><title>Scheduling Tasks in Cloud Foundry</title><link>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/scheduling-tasks-in-cloud-foundry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 14:23:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jamesclonk.io/posts/scheduling-tasks-in-cloud-foundry/</guid><description>The Task-Scheduler service on the Swisscom Application Cloud allows you to schedule and automatically run tasks for your applications. You can use it to schedule periodical execution of any tasks on the Application Cloud, including database migrations, emails, batch jobs, etc.
What are Tasks? While most of the time you are probably using the Swisscom Application Cloud (A managed Cloud Foundry platform-as-a-service) to push long running processes or &amp;ldquo;apps&amp;rdquo; as they are commonly called, there is the occasional use case for tasks.</description></item></channel></rss>